# TALIA BOWLES

#### PRODUCT AND INTERACTION DESIGNER

www.taliabowles.com

(907)947-9457

taliafbowles@gmail.com

About me:

I am a product and interaction designer who takes initiative and finds fulfillment in achieving long-term goals. My open-mindedness allowed me to gain a diverse range of professional experiences in international businesses, nonprofits, freelance work, and more. Driven to create clear and authentic designs, I revel in taking on new and unfamiliar projects.

## Experience

# 01. INTERMEDIATE INTERACTION DESIGNER

#### **Blue Shield CA**

June 2021-Present, Contract San Francisco, CA

Collaborate with project manager, lead designer and content strategist to create new and improve existing user flows.

Assist visual designers with consistency by implementing existing style guides and design patterns. Provide researchers with assets for testing to validate designs.

Sit in on grooming to guide development through user flows.

# 02. FREELANCE PRODUCT DESIGNER

Client: Tiny Docs

April 2021-June 2021

San Francisco, CA

Designed a web based health education platform for children using Figma. Used user research and interviews to inform an iterative design process. Collaborated with developers and stakeholders to launch product.

# 03. FREELANCE GRAPHIC DESIGNER

Clients: Be Joy Jewelry, C&L Creative, River Wild Camper Vans, and more

July 2020-June 2021 San Francisco, CA

Designed logos, print and digital graphics, social media content, and websites.
Utilized SEO knowledge to drive organic traffic and rank websites. Managed social media to post lx a day on instagram, facebook, and pinterest.

## 04. ASSISTANT PRODUCER

#### **Anchorage Museum**

*May 2019-February 2020* Anchorage, AK

Designed logo, social media content, book layouts, and merch using the Adobe Creative Suite to build consistent branding. Researched, designed, and produced an instructional zine to provide a more accessible form of music business education; Presented zine to music business students.

### Skills

VISUAL	uı/ux
Graphic Design	Usability Testing
Web Design	User Flows
Illustration	Wireframing
	Prototyping

### **SOFTWARE**

Adobe Illustrator Figma
Adobe XD Axure
Adobe Lightroom JIRA
Adobe InDesign Webflow

## Education

General Assembly, 2021 UX DESIGN IMMERSIVE

Loyola University New Orleans, 2016 - 2020 B.S. (HONORS) MUSIC INDUSTRY STUDIES; MINORS IN STUDIO ART & BUSINESS ADMIN.